JIHYE CHOI

San Jose, CA | 714-290-2032 | jihye1023@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jihyechoi1023/ | github.com/jhye1023

SUMMARY

Data analyst with a certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley Extension and 6+ years of experience in the financial industry. Experienced in reporting with data to facilitate executive-level decision making. Maintaining priorities on strict deadlines and a fast learner who can absorb new ideas and skills. Finds great satisfaction in extracting insights from data that inform decision-making and drive growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Flask, Matplotlib, API, JavaScript, JSON, HTML, CSS, D3, SQL, SQLAlchemy, MongoDB, Tableau, Microsoft Office

PROJECTS

Language Demographic in the US | https://github.com/tomrecht/Project-1

- Explored recent trends in the population of speakers of foreign languages in the US, both nationally and at the regional level.
- Tools used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib, Gmaps and Numpy.

New York Properties Sale |https://github.com/fsabree/final project |https://nyc-home-sale.herokuapp.com/

- Analyze and visualize the data of the sold properties in New York City during a certain time period.
- Tools used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Tableau, Plotly, AWS and Skit-learn.

EXPERIENCE

AVP & Accounting Officer Open Bank

July 2015 - February 2020

Los Angeles, CA

- Presented financial information in a clear and concise manner to management.
- Performed monthly income forecasts against annual targets.
- Simplified complex excel-based financial worksheets so reduced time to create financial reports by 50%.
- Analyzed current and past trends in key performance indicators including net interest margin, return on equity, return on assets, efficiency ratio, and book value per share.
- Updated and implemented new procedures to enhance the workflow of the accounting department.

Accounting Supervisor

September 2013 - June 2015

US Metro Bank

Garden Grove, CA

- Assisted in various accounting activities, including account payable, journal entry, bank account reconciliation and auditing.
- Supported monthly financial closing by collecting documents and ensuring all financial deadlines were met.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley Analytics and Visualization Certificate **General Assembly** SQL Bootcamp University of California, San Diego Bachelor of Arts in Economics, minor in Accounting

Berkeley, CA February 2020 - August 2020 Santa Monica, CA October 2019 San Diego, CA